import 'package:quiz007/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1.What is the capital of Thailand?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Bangkok',
      'b) Hanoi',
      'c) Seoul',
      'd) Beijing',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. What is the largest city in Brazil?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Rio de Janeiro',
      'b) São Paulo',
      'c) Brasília',
      'd) Salvador',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. What is the currency of Australia?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Euro',
      'b) Peso',
      'c) Dollar',
      'd) Australian Dollar',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. Who is the current President of the United States?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Donald Trump',
      'b) Joe Biden',
      'c) Barack Obama',
      'd) George W. Bush',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) China',
      'b) Japan',
      'c) South Korea',
      'd) Thailand',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the capital of Canada?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Toronto',
      'b) Vancouver',
      'c) Ottawa',
      'd) Montreal',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. What is the largest city in India?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Delhi',
      'b) Mumbai',
      'c) Kolkata',
      'd) Chennais',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the official language of Argentina?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Spanish',
      'b) Portuguese',
      'c) French',
      'd) English',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '9. What is the currency of South Africa?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Euro',
      'b) Dollar',
      'c) Rand',
      'd) Peso',
    ],
  ),
   Question(
    question:
        '10. What is the smallest country in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Monaco',
      'b) Maldives',
      'c) Vatican City',
      'd) Liechtenstein',
    ],
  ),
];
